<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Post-rsses on Line Of Trust</title>
    <link>https://lineoftrust.github.io/post/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Post-rsses on Line Of Trust</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 May 2017 14:40:06 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://lineoftrust.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Systematization and Project Roadmap</title>
      <link>https://lineoftrust.github.io/post/springDeliverable/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2017 14:40:06 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lineoftrust.github.io/post/springDeliverable/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;spring-deliverable&#34;&gt;Spring Deliverable&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://virginia.edu&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;University of Virginia&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s Spring 2017 &lt;a href=&#34;https://tlseminar.github.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;graduate seminar
on Transport Layer Security (TLS)&lt;/a&gt;, our project
team has continued to investigate modern issues surrounding usable privacy and
security of web browsing.
The Line of Trust project seeks to understand the security, privacy, and human-factors related to a class of phishing
and picture-in-picture attacks known collectively as the &lt;a href=&#34;https://textslashplain.com/2017/01/14/the-line-of-death/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Line of Death&lt;/a&gt;.
Contextualizing relevant literature and systematically analyzing the underlying
problems in the Line of Death space will contribute to a Systematization of
Knowledge (SoK) paper, which we intend to augment with a thoughtful user study.
The goal of this blog post is to present the culmination of our work throughout the last
six weeks of the semester and provide a roadmap for our team&amp;rsquo;s plans to move
forward through the summer months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TODO: Add anything else relevant to the project overview and this post&amp;rsquo;s
overview here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;presentation&#34;&gt;Presentation&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;script async class=&#34;speakerdeck-embed&#34;
data-id=&#34;710bc0557e1240d9a9d209d1ed14ddde&#34; data-ratio=&#34;1.33333333333333&#34;
src=&#34;//speakerdeck.com/assets/embed.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://tlseminar.github.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;TLSeminar&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s mini-conference provided our team
the opportunity to motivate and present our project work during the latter half
of the semester. Our presentation (above) focused on describing the research
problem through a case study of an elaborate picture-in-picture &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tripwire.com/state-of-security/latest-security-news/tech-support-scam-uses-website-elements-spoof-microsoft-support-page/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Microsoft Support Webpage
Scam&lt;/a&gt;
reported in March 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TODO: Talk about the presentation and its slides for a few paragraphs and relate it to what we are
posting below. In particular, discuss the relevance of the Microsoft support
picture-in-picture case study.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TODO: Describe a general introduction to the problem and why it needs attention/merits
an SoK. Should be at least a couple paragraphs with sources. To make this
easier, take a look at what we&amp;rsquo;ve written in previous posts and discussions on
the slack channel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;systematization&#34;&gt;Systematization&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TODO: Describe the general approach to our systematization (talk about the 6 questions
Bill came up with and why we choose them for our analysis). A couple paragraphs
in total should suffice. Just take the six questions below and justify/summarize
them with a few sentences each.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What problem(s) does the resource address?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How does the problem relate to web browser UI?  If so, how?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What solution(s) is proposed?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are the solutions relevant to web browser UI? If so, how?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are the pros and cons of the solutions with respect to security,
usability, and ease of adoption?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[only if viable] Based on the resource, how would you suggest proceeding with
the implementation of the solution?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;paper-1&#34;&gt;Paper 1&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TODO: Perform the systematization analysis on each paper you have read using our
methodology as described aboce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;paper-2&#34;&gt;Paper 2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;paper-n-etc&#34;&gt;Paper N &amp;hellip; etc&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion-tie-in&#34;&gt;Conclusion/Tie-In&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TODO: Relate the systematizations and discuss their purpose in our target of
motivating the need for research in the Line of Death class of attacks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;deliverable-conclusion-and-project-roadmap&#34;&gt;Deliverable Conclusion and Project Roadmap&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this blog post, we first motivated and described our semester&amp;rsquo;s efforts
towards the Line of Trust project, using our class presentation slides and a
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tripwire.com/state-of-security/latest-security-news/tech-support-scam-uses-website-elements-spoof-microsoft-support-page/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;compelling case
study&lt;/a&gt;.
Secondly, we detailed and evaluated our methodology for systematizing research
literature and community blog posts of significance to
 the Line of Death class of attacks.
Thirdly, we coalesced and analyzed a variety of literature according to our
systematization techniques, and constructed general relationships between the class of
problems uncovered in our literature systematization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the semester is coming to an end, our plans for the future of the project
are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We intend to continue work on the Line of Trust project during the summer
months, with the goal of submitting a qualitative Systematization of Knowledge
research paper to a conference in the fall term.
TODO:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discuss our goals in designing and carrying out a thoughtful user study&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discuss our goals in polishing/refining our systematization techniques&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discuss other ideas/routes/directions for the SoK that we want to consider&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TODO: Include all paper references and blog posts as links in the post&amp;rsquo;s
content. Remove this section once you&amp;rsquo;re done!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Status Update - Week 2</title>
      <link>https://lineoftrust.github.io/post/update_01/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2017 22:51:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lineoftrust.github.io/post/update_01/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;status-update-week-2&#34;&gt;Status Update - Week 2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;motivation-goals&#34;&gt;Motivation &amp;amp; Goals&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;User interfaces are vitally important components of overall security, bridging the gap that exists between system designers, security experts, and the end users for whom the systems are being designed.  In particular, the user interfaces of &lt;strong&gt;web browsers&lt;/strong&gt; prove vitally important to security given the sensitive nature of content provided by users&amp;mdash;information spanning from banking to healthcare and everything in between.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Claude Shannon, widely regarded as the &amp;ldquo;father of the information age,&amp;rdquo; aptly summarized Kerchoff&amp;rsquo;s Principle of security through open design:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;The enemy knows the system.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When applied to browser UI, it is our belief that this principle necessitates the UI be designed in such a fashion that imitation attacks&amp;mdash;one website masquerading as another&amp;mdash;must never be allowed to compromise or otherwise complicate user security.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our preliminary literature review has uncovered a myriad of shortcomings in the user interfaces of web browsers, and we have concluded that these shortcomings generally fall into two distinct categories:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inability to easily discern between trusted and untrusted content&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inability to easily validate website identities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During our review, we were quite surprised to discover an apparent dearth of academic literature specifically addressing web browser UI.  Instead, much of the existing discussion is relegated to blog posts, security articles, and developer forums.   We believe that the area of web browser UI poses a series of compelling questions deserving of dedicated analysis and research.  To this end, we seek to coalesce, assess, and expand upon existing knowledge in this domain in order to effectively systematize knowledge for the benefit of future research work.  It is our hope that this systematization of knowledge will shed light on unsolved challenges and provide a framework of prioritization that can guide researchers (and perhaps even ourselves) in improving security via better user interfaces in future work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-state-of-browser-ui-problematic&#34;&gt;The State of Browser UI:  Problematic&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;1-the-line-of-death&#34;&gt;1)  The Line of Death&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://textslashplain.com/2017/01/14/the-line-of-death/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Line of Death (LoD)&lt;/a&gt; is a class of web browser attacks that target the very pixels of a browser UI on a given webpage, especially with regards to the (presumably) browser-controlled portion of the UI above
webpage content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://lineoftrust.github.io/images/lod.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;center&gt;The Line of Death. &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://textslashplain.com/2017/01/14/the-line-of-death/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Image credit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LoD attacks span the spectrum from manipulating URL names and tabs to spoofing new browser windows within the webpage&amp;rsquo;s content area:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://lineoftrust.github.io/images/zone4.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;center&gt;Webpage controlled content. &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://textslashplain.com/2017/01/14/the-line-of-death/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Image credit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://textslashplain.com/2017/01/16/certified-malice/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Certified Malice&lt;/a&gt; is a phishing attack that deceives users into trusting a page that looks nearly identical to the real site, including TLS certificates with realistic naming schemes.  This threat becomes even more potent if combined with URL pixel manipulation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://lineoftrust.github.io/images/prompt.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;center&gt;Spoofed OS prompt in browser. &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://malwaretips.com/blogs/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/adobe-flash-palyer-outdated-virus.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Image credit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LoD attacks encompass more than just browser-object and URL spoofing attacks.  Some attacks attempt to erode users&amp;rsquo; abilities to discern legitimate OS prompts from spoofed prompts displayed in the browser, often designed to scare users into downloading or updating software.  Advanced JavaScript and HTML5 features have effectively blurred the line between browser UI and dynamically generated (and hence untrusted) page content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given the broad range of LoD-inspired attacks that have surfaced in the past year, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://lineoftrust.github.io/&#34;&gt;Line of Trust&lt;/a&gt; project seeks to generate potential solutions that improve the level of security a browser provides when trusted UI pixels and browser notifications are compromised or forged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;2-website-identity-validation-and-verification&#34;&gt;2)  Website Identity Validation and Verification&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In September of 2016, Googler Owen Campbell-Moore posted a series of thoughts on browser UI titled &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@owencm/rethinking-url-bars-as-primary-browser-ui-e2118339d2c0&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Rethinking URL bars as primary browser UI.&amp;rdquo; &lt;/a&gt;   After consulting the Google Chrome team, he came to the contentious conclusion that the URL bar may be an anachronism in the reality of today&amp;rsquo;s Web, kept alive for the historical reason of &amp;ldquo;we&amp;rsquo;ve always done it that way.&amp;rdquo;  He specifically identified three primary reasons why UI designers have retained the URL bar:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;So users understand who they&amp;rsquo;re talking to&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;So users can know where on a site they are, and navigate by modifying the URL&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;So users can share links to what they&amp;rsquo;re currently looking at&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Campbell-Moore notes that today&amp;rsquo;s URL &amp;ldquo;omnibar&amp;rdquo; is responsible for far too many aspects of the browser UI to be effective (site identity, location within the site, security status, geographic location indicator, pop-up control, plug-in status) and argues that these constraints should be satisfied via alternative methods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In essence, he offers that (1) and (2) are not compelling enough reasons to maintain the URL bar.  In its place, he suggests establishing an &lt;em&gt;origin-to-local-brand-mapping system&lt;/em&gt;, managed by search engines (presumably Google), that would serve to validate the identities of a certain subset of popular websites, displaying trusted identity information where the complicated URL omnibar is presently situated.  (And, of course, this identity information would be unspoofable, much like how &amp;ldquo;www.facebook.com&amp;rdquo; belongs to Facebook and cannot be issued to anyone else.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;When a user is on Facebook, why doesn&amp;rsquo;t the URL bar just say &amp;lsquo;Facebook,&amp;rsquo; with a small Facebook logo?  Would that not more clearly help the user understand the literal origin of the content?  Clearly, we would need a way for browsers to determine the locally known brand name and logo of all sites.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We believe that Campbell-Moore has raised a hugely important point, even if abolishing the URL bar may be infeasible:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If we were to redesign the web browser UI from scratch, how would we do it?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is our hope that a potential answer to this question would effectively thwart all the aforementioned UI shortcomings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;moving-forward&#34;&gt;Moving Forward&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given the shortcomings and opportunities for study identified above, we plan to investigate four areas in the realm of usable browser security: spoofing legitimate browser UI elements, picture-in-picture attacks, exact reproductions of websites, and full browser UI redesigns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For each of these four areas, we will follow a specific system, defined below, for gathering and analyzing information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;First, we determine what past work has been done in that area, as well as relevant security problems.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Next, we examine old solutions to these early problems. These solutions patch and target specific types of attacks, and are very narrow in scope. Many of these solutions are therefore obsolete due to more recent changes in web usage, such as HTML5 and browser modifications. However, these new developments yield new problems within their respective areas.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;We devise various potential unbounded solutions to these problems and categorize them into three types:   UI solutions (which deal with user awareness), experimental techniques (solutions based on vision, NLP, and other cutting edge techniques), and infrastructure redesign (solutions that require more extensive change, potentially even beyond the browser).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stage 1 is underway and will soon transition to stage 2.  The target deliverable on April 28th is a quality SoK that will define the problem, provide our preliminary reasoning on the issues at stake, suggest some potential avenues to fix the problems, and conclude with open research questions.  We intend to carefully reason about underlying connections among the UI issues that may point toward a common &amp;ldquo;best&amp;rdquo; solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;relevant-resources&#34;&gt;Relevant Resources&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://textslashplain.com/2017/01/14/the-line-of-death/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The Line of Death - Text/Plain&lt;/a&gt;  Details of spoofed browser prompts, untrusted and trusted information zones, and picture-in-picture attacks&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@owencm/rethinking-url-bars-as-primary-browser-ui-e2118339d2c0&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Rethinking URL bars as primary browser UI&lt;/a&gt; Replace the browser URL bar with an &amp;ldquo;identity bar&amp;rdquo; managed by search engines, since &amp;ldquo;no one uses the URL bar anymore&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.w3.org/2005/Security/usability-ws/papers/02-hp-petname/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;PetNames&lt;/a&gt; Associate a catchphrase with trusted websites in order to quickly identify fraudulent copies of the websites (evident if the catchphrase is absent)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tripwire.com/state-of-security/latest-security-news/tech-support-scam-uses-website-elements-spoof-microsoft-support-page/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Microsoft Support Page - LoD Attack&lt;/a&gt; Very recent LoD attack on the Microsoft Support Page; takes advantage of fullscreen HTML5&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://books.google.com/books?id=xxAbEcNlIwwC&amp;amp;pg=PA499&amp;amp;lpg=PA499&amp;amp;dq=spoofed+browser+elements&amp;amp;source=bl&amp;amp;ots=JUoFxxxosB&amp;amp;sig=rVMyxVbg6eKAmRiiRJYBWL76bIY&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ved=0ahUKEwjqwrLXo_jSAhXM7CYKHeSyBZcQ6AEIHDAA#v=onepage&amp;amp;q=spoofed%20browser%20elements&amp;amp;f=false&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Verification Engine&lt;/a&gt; LoD defense mechanism c. 2006 that highlights the borders of trusted UI elements when the mouse hovers over them (could be mimicked with advanced JavaScript and HTML5 today)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://crypto.stanford.edu/SpoofGuard/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;SpoofGuard&lt;/a&gt;  Tactics to defend against fraudulent websites c. 2004; most of the techniques are outdated now&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://eprint.iacr.org/2004/155.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;TrustBar&lt;/a&gt; Suggests that &amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip;a realistic usability test should provide a reasonable level of introduction of any new mechanism, balancing this with the risk of causing users to be overly-aware of security.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;contributors&#34;&gt;Contributors&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anant Kharkar, undergraduate student at the University of Virginia&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sam Havron, undergraduate student at the University of Virginia&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bill Young, graduate student at the University of Virginia&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Joshua Holtzman, undergraduate student at the University of Virginia&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dave Evans, project advisor and computer science professor at the University of Virginia&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome!</title>
      <link>https://lineoftrust.github.io/post/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2017 13:51:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lineoftrust.github.io/post/welcome/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;introducing-the-line-of-trust-lotr&#34;&gt;Introducing the Line of Trust (LOTr)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Erasing the line of death for fun and pleasure&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;motivation&#34;&gt;Motivation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://textslashplain.com/2017/01/14/the-line-of-death/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Line of Death (LoD)&lt;/a&gt; is a class of web
browser attacks that target the very pixels of a browser UI on a given webpage,
especially with regards to the (presumably) browser-controlled portion of the UI above
webpage content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://lineoftrust.github.io/images/lod.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;center&gt;The Line of Death. &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://textslashplain.com/2017/01/14/the-line-of-death/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Image credit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LoD attacks span the spectrum from manipulating URL names and tabs to spoofing new browser windows within the
webpage&amp;rsquo;s content area:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://lineoftrust.github.io/images/zone4.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;center&gt;Webpage controlled content. &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://textslashplain.com/2017/01/14/the-line-of-death/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Image credit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://textslashplain.com/2017/01/16/certified-malice/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Certified Malice&lt;/a&gt; is a
phishing attack that deceives users into trusting a page that looks nearly identical
to the real site, including TLS certificates with realistic naming schemes.
This threat becomes even more potent if combined with URL pixel manipulation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://lineoftrust.github.io/images/prompt.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;center&gt;Spoofed OS prompt in browser. &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://malwaretips.com/blogs/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/adobe-flash-palyer-outdated-virus.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Image credit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LoD attacks encompass more than just browser-object and URL spoofing attacks.  Some attacks
attempt to erode users&amp;rsquo; abilities to discern legitimate OS prompts from spoofed prompts
displayed in the browser, often designed to scare users into downloading or updating software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given the broad range of LoD-inspired attacks that have surfaced in the past
year, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://lineoftrust.github.io/&#34;&gt;Line of Trust&lt;/a&gt; project seeks to improve the level of security a
browser provides when trusted UI pixels and browser notifications are compromised or forged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;goals-for-line-of-trust&#34;&gt;Goals for Line of Trust&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Specifically, we are interested in developing baked-in browser warnings for content that is
suspected to be a LoD attack. We will be using &lt;a href=&#34;https://chromium.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Google
Chromium&lt;/a&gt; to develop LOTr.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our overarching goal is to reduce the feasibility of LoD attacks while providing
increased transparency to the end-user. We are currently considering various computer
vision techniques to build LOTr.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;relevant-resources&#34;&gt;Relevant Resources&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;News, Blogs, &amp;amp; Forums&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=13400291&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The Line of Death - Hacker News&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://textslashplain.com/2017/01/14/the-line-of-death/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The Line of Death - Text/Plain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;contributors&#34;&gt;Contributors&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anant Kharkar, undergraduate student at the University of Virginia&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sam Havron, undergraduate student at the University of Virginia&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bill Young, graduate student at the University of Virginia&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Joshua Holtzman, undergraduate student at the University of Virginia&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dave Evans, project advisor and computer science professor at the University of Virginia&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>